MARIA LIBERTO

>>310 E. Evergreen Ave



Philadelphia, PA 19118

> 484.626.3240

> mlibe590@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Attentive Elementary / Special Education Teacher with excellent communication and organizational skills. Four years experience teaching students with emotional behavior disorders. Comfortable collaborating with colleagues and paraprofessionals. My 5-year plan includes returning to graduate school and study to become an Applied Behavior Analysis.

EXPERIENCE

Knights Elementary I Plant City, Florida I Principal Janine Hall

Contact number: 813.757.9333

K-2 EBD Teacher | August 2016-May 2017

Simmons Exceptional Centerl Plant City, Florida I Principal Cleto Chazares

Contact number: 813.707.7430

4-5 EBD Teacher | August 2012-June 2016

Roles and Responsibilities:

- Conducted small group and individualized instruction based on students' needs and behaviors.
- Communicated daily with parents / guardians to create a supportive and cohesive learning environment.
- Collaborated with collogues to lesson plan and differentiate instruction to meet the diverse needs of the students.
- Delegated and supervised paraprofessionals inside the classroom to ensure safety and productivity throughout the school day.
- Tracked student behavior and graphed results.
- Reviewed and revised Individualized Education Plans to meet the current needs of the student.

EDUCATION

Kutztown University I Kutztown, Pennsylvania

Elementary & Special Education

December 2012

AWARDS AND ACKNOWLEDGEMENTS

- Passed all Praxis Series Tests
- Professional Educator's Certificate for Florida Grades K-6
- Received Highly Effective evaluations 2014-2015.
- Nominated for the Excellence in Action Awards in 2015 by a parent.
- Awarded best new teacher 2014.